Thank you for watching
Almighty Presents Delivering Funfami Newly Selected and
What % of what you eat is domestically produced?
Food self-sufficiency and self-sufficiency
Bon appétit!
It's finally started! Season 4 of Delivering Pampas!
Well, I've been asked to do this by people from the future.
Well, it's our future, too.
Hey, Matoba!
Let me explain.
Matoba-chan is an idol from the future Japan.
In the future, the world is full of hungry people.
And the world is in trouble.
To save the world of the future
She has crossed time and space
and came to Japan in the year 2023.
Who made these omusubi?
Who made these diapers?
I made them with my own hands.
What do you think? What's your score, Ao-chan?
A perfect score of 100.
Yay!
That's great. You got 100 points.
How about you, Chan-chan?
Out of 100.
1,200,000 points!
That's amazing!
You're out of ideas.
It's too much.
1.2 million points.
Matoba?
Yes, that's right.
Ninety-eighth place.
Oh! Two more points!
So close!
Where did you get the other two?Where's the other two?
But you know what?
This miso soup is delicious, too.
Who made this miso soup?
I made that one.
By the way, what's the score?
100 points, of course.
Thank you very much.
I'm glad.
I'm sure you got 100 for this one, right, Mr. Tomochi?
29. Result?
He's a grimy miso soup maker. - He's a grimy miso soup maker.
By the way, this omelet is 13.
13?
And this sausage is 7.
7!
Okay, you look good for a 7.
Yes! No, no, no, no, no, no.
It's not about the score.
It's about food self-sufficiency.
Food self-sufficiency?
Yes, it's a measure of the percentage of food we eat
It's a measure of the percentage of the food we eat that is self-sufficient in the country.
It's the first thing I want you to know when you think about food security and the significance of choosing local products.
This is the first thing you need to know.
But this omelette...
They're straight from the hen's eggs.
Why are they so low?
Surprising, isn't it?
The chickens that lay the eggs are fed corn.
Most of it is imported.
That's why the self-sufficiency rate is so low.
So, the first workshop is
How about a project to let people know about food self-sufficiency?
That's what I'm thinking. I've already prepared it.
Chan-chan, please.Chan-chan, please.
Yes, the first commemorative edition
Food self-sufficiency Self-sufficiency section
Please go ahead!
Thank you for watching!
ungef mukan ha moopa
blop kan 2
Gel.
I think it's going to be less and less!
Even Golbei Season 4 Workshop for the commemoration of the anniversary is
Then, what you eat is homegrown food!
Food self-sufficiency, self-sufficiency!
[Applause] Yes, we're done.
Yes, we're done. Deliver! Fun Farm Season 4.
Our plan for Season 4 is to think about the significance of choosing homegrown food,
We will be presenting it in a workshop format with viewer participation.
Oh!
The first progression comes to you from Mirai.
I, Matoma and,
Osetsu and I am Osetsu from today. Thank you very much for your cooperation.
With everyone who will be participating in this workshop,
I am Matoma, Osetsu, and I'm Osetsu, and we are the four members of Nishino Conquistadors.
I look forward to working with you.
Four people. I am one of the four Conquistadors.
There are four of us. Thank you for putting this together.
It was written in the script, in case you were wondering,
I look forward to working with you.
I am Nishino Conquistador.
Thank you for your time.
In Season 4, we have a big theme that is a bit difficult to deal with: food security,
It is the idea that we should produce our own food in our own country,
We are going to look into and learn from various aspects of this concept.
The first session, which should be commemorated, will be on food self-sufficiency and self-sufficiency.
This sounds quite difficult, but how are you feeling about it?
At this point, I think it is quite difficult and there are a lot of kanji characters.
I'm at the stage of looking at the characters.It's now at the stage of looking at the letters.
So let's get started right away. I look forward to working with you all.
Thank you very much for your cooperation.
Let's begin the first workshop on food self-sufficiency and self-sufficiency,
Do you know what self-sufficiency in food self-sufficiency is?
If you do, or if you are one of them, I would like you to raise your hand.
Do I have to explain it to you? Please don't tell me.
I don't care if it's just a hunch.
Ah, there you are.
I think it is the rate of how much of what we produce in our own country can be supplied by the people of our own country.
I think it's a rate of how much we can supply.
I don't know if I'm explaining it well.
Excellent!
The correct answer is this.
It is the percentage of our country that is self-sufficient in the food we eat.
That's wonderful.
Food self-sufficiency refers to the potential production capacity.
And you see, there are two ways to calculate food self-sufficiency,
The first one is calories, calorific value.
The first is the calorie pace, which is calculated in terms of calories and calories per unit of production.
The second is the pace of production value, which is converted into monetary value, and is used as an indicator of the percentage of domestic production.
So now, ladies and gentlemen, here is the question.
Do you know what Japan's current food self-sufficiency rate is in terms of calories per unit of production in the three fiscal years?
This is quite difficult. This is an intuition.
Please think about it.
What do you think Japan's current food self-sufficiency rate is?
Shall we go then?
Yes, I do.
3%.
I see.
The example is three years old.
Well, it's accurate.
I'm surprised you raised your hand first.
Well, let's see.
Thirty-eight.
Oh!Ooh.
You went with 3 points.
You said up to 38.
I don't know how many of you are that high.
How many of you think it's 10%?
How many of you think it's between 10 and 20
Between 20 and 30.
That's a lot.
Between 30 and 40.
Between 30 and 40
40 to 50.
Almost all of them already.
More than 50
Sixty and up.
Why?
Because I thought you meant less than half.
I'd say less than half.
That's what you're expecting.
I see.
Please tell me the correct answer.
The correct answer is
38% of us.
That's amazing.
He's definitely been studying.
It's real.
I'd say he's done his homework.
Three questions for you.
What percentage of Japan imports food?
Imports?
Do you know what imports are?
Imports from different countries.
We are 38% self-sufficient.
Yes, sir.
Calculate.
CalculateCalculation
82%.
Wait a minute.
What kind of calculation is this?
Just the formula
Not even close
Just tell me the formula.
If the self-sufficiency rate is 38%...
The remaining 82%...
Isn't that 90%?
The rest, right?
That's a lot of leftovers.
72%.
Huh? Wait a minute, I made a mistake.
I'm sorry, Mr. Target, but I'm going to have to ask you to answer.
62% are imported from overseas.
The answer is 62%.
Subtract 100.
The formula was correct.
It's just that it's 110% or something.
That was close.
Is this more or less?
I'm going to look at past self-sufficiency rates.
And here's the question for you all again.
Fifty years ago.
In 1973, what was the food self-sufficiency rate?
What was the percentage?
I would like you to answer this question on a calorie basis.
I would like you to answer.
Now, let's see.
In 1973, 50 years ago.
What was the food self-sufficiency rate?
It was 1973.
Let's ask everyone.
50 years ago.It was 50 years ago.
58, I guess.
A little higher than now.
higher than now.
Is it higher than 58?
Is 58 the standard?
On the contrary.
Do you think it was lower than 38?
Yes.
Yes, there are.
Do you think it's between 10 and 20?
What do you think?
I think it's low.
I don't know if any of you are low... 20 to 30.
I think it's more, it's more, it's more... I'm guessing... 40 to 50.
Oh, 50 to 60.
60 to 70%.
That's great.
The correct answer is...
55%.
Yay!
That's close enough.
Due to the change in diet, Japan's food insecurity rate has increased over the past 50 years.
Japan's food insecurity rate has dropped by a whopping 20% over the past 50 years.
has dropped by about 20% over the past 50 years.
In light of this situation
Japan is aiming to raise the ratio from 38% to 45% by 2025.
to 45% by the year 2025.
Japan has set a goal of raising the food wage rate from 38% to 45% by 2025.
I understand that the hourly wage rate is lower than in the past.
I think there are some changes in diet and so on.
But it's still low compared to other countries, isn't it?
That's right.
Please take a look at this.
It may be a little hard to see.
Canada, Australia, the U.S., France, Germany, England, Italy, Switzerland, and Japan.Canada Australia USA France Germany UK Italy Switzerland and Japan
Wow.
That's pretty low.
It's very low.
When you look at it in comparison
This food self-sufficiency rate
Why should we raise this food self-sufficiency rate?
I'll give you a brief summary.
Here it is
World population growth, endemic climate, human life, annual diseases, international customs, and so on...
Due to various factors
It is expected to become difficult to import from overseas.
Therefore
We should make our own food in our own country.
Therefore, it is very important for us to make our own food in our own country.
It will become very important to produce our own food in our own country.
I see.
Now, from here...
What is the percentage of food self-sufficiency of the food we eat?
What is the percentage of food self-sufficiency
What is the percentage of food self-sufficiency?
So...
Yes, sir.
I've never really thought about it.
That's right.
I mean, I'm not really aware of it.
I've never thought about it.
Then, here...
Here's your problem, Ao.
Ao-chan.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Okay, okay.
Here we go.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Tempura udon, ume plum rice balls, okonomiyaki, pork cutlet on rice.Tempura udon Udon plum rice balls Okonomiyaki Katsudon
List them in order of food self-sufficiency.
Please think about it for a moment.
Please think about it.
All of them can be called Japanese food.
But what about the self-sufficiency rate?
That's right, isn't it?
Then, ume rice balls!
Ume onigiri is the best!
Katsu-don (pork cutlet served on top of a bowl of rice)
Because there is a lot of rice in it
Tempura udon with
and Okonomiyaki
I see.
The correct answer is
It's perfect.
That's great.
I barely answered any of them.
That's great. That's a lot.
That's great.
Udon noodles and okonomiyaki is a bit of a trick.
I made it myself.
Okonomiyaki is 18%.
I think it's a very Japanese food.
Actually, 18% is kind of low.
Surprisingly low.
Next, let's see...
What was the percentage of food self-sufficiency for today's breakfast?
The Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries has created a software to easily calculate the self-sufficiency rate of food.
I'd like you to find out by using the self-sufficiency rate calculation software created by the Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries of Japan.
I see you have something like this
This way
Yes, it's like this.
This is great!
So, you'll all get it.
Oh!Oh.
I see.
This is starting to sound like a workshop.
So you're going to do some calculations.
What is the food self-sufficiency rate of the food
What is the self-sufficiency rate of the food you eat?
Please try to find out what the self-sufficiency rate of food is.
Please do a search for "food self-sufficiency rate calculation".
And please let us know in the comments section how much of your breakfast is self-sufficient.
Did you do the math, folks? Are you okay?
I'd like you to have it handy, but I'm going to ask Marina first.
I ate two breakfasts today.
What's so funny?
In the Toxila case.
I ate twice in the Toxila case.
The first thing I ate at home was tomato juice.
And then, since there was no item called protein, I had milk with protein mixed in.
And then, with the one I was fed earlier, omusubi.
And miso soup. Tofu and wakame seaweed miso soup.
And fried egg. I made it on this basis.
I calculated that our food self-sufficiency ratio on a calorie basis is 58%.
Then, please.
Please.
As if they weren't there.
Do you want me to start with this?
From Kondate.
Today I had natto rice and some chicken stew.
The food self-sufficiency rate based on calories is 56%.
That's about the same.
It's about the same as if you eat a little bit of food.
Isn't it surprisingly low?
I feel like it's good.
It's not good.
I see.
Let's start with the rice pudding.
I have two hot dogs, fried chicken, and tomato juice.The condiment is two hot dogs, fried chicken and tomato juice.
I did the math and found that the calorie base is ?
Calorie base is 16%.
That's very low.
Low.
That's low.
I ate the bread and the compoterege.
Calorie base is 27%.
Welcome back.
What do you want to do?
I didn't actually eat breakfast today.
Considering it's the one I usually eat.
fried egg, rice, natto and milk.
And that's 69% of my calorie base.
Wow!
So I asked you to calculate it for me.
Now that you know what you are eating is 69% of your calories
Now we would like to have a showdown!
The title is "Ideal Curry and Rice Present!
Please explain the rules, Mr. Ose.
We're going to divide you into three teams and ask you to come up with your ideal curry and rice.
You'll create the finished product, a drawing, and the ingredients.
Each team will give a presentation.
The judge, Kyota, will score the ideal curry and rice recipe out of 100 points.
This will be based on the picture, ingredients and presentation.
Then, the endurance rate of the recipe's ingredients will be calculated.
That number, or percentage, is added to the score.
The team with the most points wins!
By the way, there is a prize for the winning team!
What is Kyota's favorite curry rice?
Favorite curry and rice
Two specific points will be related to this question.
I love curry rice with large ingredients.
It's more satisfying when it has a lot of big ingredients in it.
That is my favorite curry rice.That is my favorite curry and rice!
While this is also a hint
Yes.
Or you can aim for food self-sufficiency and ignore Kyoto's preference.
Or, you could throw away the points.
I'm a judge, so you'll have to worry about me.
I'll be moaning, so that's about it, and I can't go in there.
So, what did you think?
Let's go! The second session of Fun Farm Season 4...
Our first attempt at a workshop!
This season, we would like to think about the future of food in Japan
We would like to think about the future of food in Japan!
Sounds interesting! If you are interested in participating
Please apply for the workshop!
Next time: The second half of the self-sufficiency in food self-sufficiency section!
Please look forward to seeing what kind of ideal curry we can make!